Finding Aid for the Belle Kinney and Leopold Scholz Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
Belle Kinney and Leopold Scholz Papers
multiple
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
MSS.0639
3.75 linear_feet
Biography/History
The following is a list of the compositions, portrait busts, reliefs, etc. created by Belle Kinney Scholz individually, or in collaboration with Leopold F. Scholz:
1908 – Richard Owen Memorial - State Capitol, Indiana
1913 – Joseph G. Johnston statue- Dalton, GA
1917 – Monument for State of Mississippi
1919 – General A. P. Stewart- Chattanooga, TN
1923 - Restoration and re-creation of the two pediments for the Nashville Reproduction of the original Parthenon at Athens, Greece
1926 - Philip Lindsley Memorial -Peabody College in Nashville, TN
1926 – Monument to Women of the Confederacy- Nashville, TN
1928 – Portrait bust of Andrew Jackson- Hall of Fame, New York University
1928 – Portrait statue of Andrew Jackson- U.S. Capitol, Washington, DC
1929 - Victory statue for the Tennessee World War Memorial- Nashville, TN
1931 - Portrait statue of General John Sevier- U.S. Capitol, Washington, DC
1933 – Victory statue for the New York City World War Memorial
1938 – Portrait bust of Admiral Albert Gleaves- U.S. Naval Academy, Annapolis, MD
Scope and Contents
The collection will be divided into the following series:
Series I- Outgoing correspondence (includes copybooks)
Series II - Incoming correspondence
Series III- Newspaper clippings
Series IV -Programs/Flyers
Series V - Sketchbooks
Series VI- Sketches
Series VII - Blue-line drawings
Series VIII - Photographs
Series IX- Literary Soul-Maker, 1922 -Play
Series X - Real Estate Taxes Cancelled Checks
- Series I- Outgoing Correspondence
  - to Surgeon General Gorgas, June 7, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - to Mr. Edward E. Daugherty, April 11, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - to Mr. Walter Stokes Jr., May 22, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - to Mr. Hart, June 28, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - to Mr. H. L. McFadden, July 1929 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - to Belle from Leopold, October 9, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - to Mr. Rogers Caldwell, October 24, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - to Mrs. Bashinsky, January 1, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - to Mrs. Milton (2 copies), January 6, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - to Mrs. Gillentine, January 6, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - to Tennessee War Memorial Commission, February 4, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - to John F. Nolan, March 27, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - to Henry Norton (2 copies), August 14, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - to W. M. Dean Marble Company, December 30, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - to W. M. Dean Marble Company, January 29, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - to Maine & New Hampshire Granite Corporation, January 29, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - to Kunst Art Foundries (2 copies), May 12, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - to Mr. Collins, July 29, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - to John J. Sheridan, December 17, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - to Thomas J. Dolan, December 17, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - to Railways Express Agency, August 15, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - to Charles Little, August 18, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - to Mrs. De La Bane, February 14, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - to Fireman’s Fund Indemnity, April 2, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - to Mrs. Trager, July 20, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - to Mrs. Sara P. Bradford, July 20, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - April 4, 1934 to July 6, 1934 (copybook) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - to Mr. J. J. Haverty, November 23, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - to Mr. Henkel, January 8, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Painting and Sculpture Section, December 4, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - November 11, 1936 to April23, 1938 (copybook) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - to Ladies Hermitage Association, October 26, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - to Dr. Capps, November 26, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - to Dr. Merritt, December 14, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - to Mr. Happer, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - to Mr. Henslee, February 1940 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - to Cordell Hull, January 28, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - to Governor Cooper, July 10, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - to Mr. Horn, July 10, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - to Mr. Beard, July 12, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - to Walter Chandler, July 22, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - to Walter Chandler (2 copies), October 3, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - to Mr. Tupper, January 24, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - to Mr. Hom, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - to Mr. Warfield, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - to Mr. Warfield, April 30, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - to Zelia, June 23, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Series 11-lncoming Correspondence
  - September 21, 1908 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - March 2, 1909 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - November 21, 1911 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - February 16, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - October 24, 1912 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - November 10, 1913 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - April13, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - September 16, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - October 21, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - November 25, 1914 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - May 14, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - August 1, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - October 3, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - November 23, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - June 12, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - November 7, 1916 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - April 20, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - November 15, 1917 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - August 23, 1921 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - April 12, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - December 30, 1922 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - February 21, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - April 18, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - May 11, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - May 24, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - May 26, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - June 1, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - October 9, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - November 6, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - March 1, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - March 7, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - May 12, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - May 16, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - June 23, 1924 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - January 21, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - March 19, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - March 31, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - April 1, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - April 8, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - April 11, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - April 20, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - May 30, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - August 5, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - September 12, 1915 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - September 19, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - October 6, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - October 9, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - December 14, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - March 24, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - April 12, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - November 15, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - January 15, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - March 25, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - May 4, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - May 14, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - May 27, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - October 29, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - November 29, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - December 19, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - December 21, 1927 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - January 31, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - February 3, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - March 10, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - March 22, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - April 16, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - April 17, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - April 20, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - April 20, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - April 20, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - April 21, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - April 29, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - July 3, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - August 16, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - September 6, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - September 11, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - September 12, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - October 12, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - November 23, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - December 14, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - December 14, 1928 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - January 9, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - March 4, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - April 17, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - April 29, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - May 1, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - May 1, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - May 10, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - May 17, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - May 23, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - May 31, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - June 7, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - June 11, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - June 13, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - June 13, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - June 14, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - June 18, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - June 20, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - July 1, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - July 1, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - July 12, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - July 24, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - August 15, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - August 16, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - September 26, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - September 30, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - October 1, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - October 1, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - October 1, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - October 2, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - October 4, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - October 8, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - October 13, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - October 13, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - October 17, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - October 17, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - October 18, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - October 28, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - November 6, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - November 7, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - November 7, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - November 13, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - November 20, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - November 22, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - December 2, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - December 2, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - December 5, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - December 30, 1929 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - January 6, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - January 6, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - January 7, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - January 8, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - January 9, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - January 14, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - January 15, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - January 15, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - January 21, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - January 21, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - January 22, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - January 24, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - February 7, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - February 25, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - March 8, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - March 25, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - March 31, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - April 2, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - April 16, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - April 16, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - May 3, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - May 7, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - May 20, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - June 6, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - June 19, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - June 27, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - June 30, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - July 7, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - July 21, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - August 5, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - September 11, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - September 23, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - September 25, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - October 28, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - October 29, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - November 5, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - November 17, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - December 2, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - December 3, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - December 3, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - December 4, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - December 5, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - December 5, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - December 12, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - January 2, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - January 3, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - January 6, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - February 12, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - February 14, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - March 6, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - March 16, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - March 21, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - March 23, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - March 24, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - April 1, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - April 17, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - April 18, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - April 21, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - May 6, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - May 6, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - June 29, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - July 8, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - July 22, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - December 16, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - December 16, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- January 1932 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- January 19, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- February 1, 1923 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- March 2, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- March 14, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- March 19, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- May 16, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- May 19, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- June 4, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- June 8, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- June 17, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- July 21, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- July 22, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- July 22, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- July 26, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- July 29, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- August 2, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- August 23, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- September 4, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- September 26, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- September 26, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- October 3, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- October 10, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- October 10, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- October 17, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- November 19, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- November 28, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- December 1, 1932 (Box 3, Folder 2)